<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sharp Bell</title>
    <description>Personal blog of Osvaldo Zagordi, data scientist at University of Zurich and founder of enGene Statistics. Data science, statistics, science, machine learning, python, R and so on.
</description>
    <link>https://ozagordi.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://ozagordi.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 10:55:49 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 10:55:49 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The most important concept</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If we had to choose a single statement to pass to generations after an
imaginary destruction of the whole scientific knowledge, what would you choose?
Which idea would help the subsequent generations the most in recreating the
lost body of knowledge and, ultimately, the civilization? Richard Feynman once
stated that it is the atomic hypothesis,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
that all things are made of atoms—little particles that move around in perpetual
motion, attracting each other when they are a little distance apart, but
repelling upon being squeezed into one another.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This struck me again a few days ago when a new coworker started here and I was
asked to introduce her to (loosely speaking) data analysis and computation.
Since years now, I’ve been working mainly with people without a strong
mathematical background. I’ve always done my best to explain things
from my side, and I’ve always been irritated by scientists who try to
impress/humiliate others with some “theorem dropping”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/figure/source/2016-07-06-most-important-concept/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk unnamed-chunk-1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you had to choose one single concept that a person absolutely needs to
grasp before endeavouring in data analysis, what should this concept be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe it is the concept of function in mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://ozagordi.github.io/2016/07/06/most-important-concept/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ozagordi.github.io/2016/07/06/most-important-concept/</guid>
        
        <category>fundamentals</category>
        
        <category>science</category>
        
        <category>mathematics</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
